Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是斯科特-曼利
Yesterday Roscosmos announced the crew for two Soyuz missions
昨天 俄罗斯航天局宣布了两次联盟号任务的机组人员名单
which will carry tourists to the International Space Station in October and December.
将在10月和12月携带游客前往国际空间站
Now if we add that into Inspiration 4 which will fly in September.
现在 如果我们把它加入到将于9月飞行的Inspiration 4中
Axiom's AX-1 flight which could be as early as January 2022
Axiom公司的AX-1飞行可能最早于2022年1月进行
and a possible future flight by Tom Cruise to shoot a movie.
以及汤姆-克鲁斯未来可能的飞行 以拍摄一部电影
This means there's gonna be a lot more tourists in space than ever before.
这意味着将有比以往更多的游客进入太空
And actually before that we are expecting the first flight of New Shepard with an actual paying passenger
而实际上在此之前 我们期待着新谢泼德号的首次飞行 并有真正的付费乘客
after Blue Origin announced an auction for the very first seat alongside five Blue Origin employees.
在蓝色起源宣布拍卖第一个座位和五名蓝色起源员工之后
There's no firm date for this but it could be as early as July.
目前还没有确定的日期 但可能最早在7月
So I'm actually kind of surprised that in the world of space tourism
所以我实际上有点惊讶 在太空旅游的世界里
suborbital tourist flights never managed to get going in great numbers before well now.
亚轨道旅游飞行在现在之前从未成功地进行过大量的飞行
A Virgin Galactic got going long before SpaceX began developing Crew Dragon
维珍银河公司早在SpaceX开始开发 "乘龙 "号之前就已经开始了
but it's been cursed by all sorts of problems
但它一直被各种问题所困扰着
including a crash which killed one of their pilots and destroyed their spacecraft.
包括一次坠机 导致他们的一名飞行员死亡 并摧毁了他们的航天器
They've carried one passenger to space who was worked with a company
他们曾将一名在一家公司工作的乘客送上太空
and then after that they moved their base from California to spaceport New Mexico
之后 他们将基地从加利福尼亚搬到了新墨西哥州的太空港
and pretty much stopped flying for two years.
并几乎停止了两年的飞行
Blue Origin meanwhile they've had lots of successful tests of New Shepard.
同时 蓝色起源公司对新谢泼德进行了大量成功的测试
They've generated lots of flight data.
他们已经产生了大量的飞行数据
They've shown that the vehicle is safe and reliable and definitely okay to put humans on.
他们已经表明 该飞行器是安全和可靠的 绝对可以让人类乘坐
New Shepard are actually arguably provides a superior experience in many ways
新谢泼德号实际上可以说在许多方面提供了一种优越的体验
with much larger windows and a bit more room to move around.
有更大的窗户和更多的活动空间
although you can't look straight down as you can in spaceship two
尽管你不能像在二号飞船中那样直视下方
because it flips on its back during apogee
因为它在远地点会翻转到背面
so you can actually see the earth laid out below you.
所以你实际上可以看到地球就在你下面
So yeah I mean these sub-orbital flights
所以是的 我的意思是这些亚轨道飞行
are hundreds of thousands of dollars for a few minutes of weightlessness
几十万美元就能享受几分钟的失重状态
and a wonderful view from above the karman line
和从卡曼线以上的美妙景色
but if you just want zero g by the way
但是 如果你只是想获得零重力 顺便说一下
you can actually pay for parabolic flights
你实际上可以支付抛物线飞行
and those only cost a few thousand dollars for many short hops of 30 seconds or more
而那些只需几千美元就能实现30秒或更短的飞行时间
but anyway for the orbital flights in the next 12 months we can expect to have a number of flights.
但无论如何 在未来12个月的轨道飞行中 我们可以期待有一些飞行
We're going to start with Inspiration 4 in September
我们将从9月的Inspiration 4开始
and this is going to be a free-flying Dragon flight
这将是一次自由飞行的龙飞船飞行
which won't go to the International Space Station
它不会去国际空间站
and that meant that it avoided scheduling problems with the station's very limited docking adapters.
而这意味着它避免了与空间站非常有限的对接适配器的时间安排问题
The crew of four will spend three days in orbit.
四名船员将在轨道上停留三天
And they'll be actually at a higher altitude than the International Space Station
而且他们实际上将处于比国际空间站更高的高度上
but because they're inside a single Dragon capsule
但由于他们在一个单一的龙舱内
they won't have much room to move around and do back flips and stuff like that
他们不会有太多的空间来移动和做后空翻之类的事情
but they will have fantastic views better views than you would get from the space station arguably.
但他们会有很好的视野 可以说比你从空间站得到的视野更好
Now since it's not docking to the International Space Station
现在 由于它没有与国际空间站对接
the docking system at the front will be replaced with a transparent dome
前面的对接系统将被替换成一个透明的圆顶
to allow the passengers to stick their head in
让乘客可以把头伸进去
and experience really wide angle vistas of the earth in space.
并体验太空中地球的真正广角视野
The Dragon spacecraft that they're going to use by the way is Resilience
顺便说一下 他们将使用的 "龙 "飞船是 "复原 "号
that's the spacecraft that was used by Crew-1
那是船员1号使用的航天器
which just returned to earth after their six-month flight to the ISS.
在国际空间站飞行6个月后刚刚返回地球
So the crew for Inspiration for are Jared Isaacman who's a pilot and a businessman.
因此 "灵感号 "的船员是贾里德-艾萨克曼 他是一名飞行员 也是一名商人
He's footing the bill for the whole thing.
他为整个事情买单
There's Hayley Arceneaux who's a physician within St. Jude.
Hayley Arceneaux是圣裘德医院的一名医生
There's Dr. Sian Proctor, a science communicator on youtube and everything.
还有Sian Proctor博士 他是Youtube上的科学传播者和所有的人
And Christopher Sembroski who he's been a space fan for a long time.
还有克里斯托弗-森布罗斯基 他是一个很长时间的太空迷
And he more or less won a lottery ticket to get on his flight.
他或多或少赢得了一张彩票 以登上他的航班
Technically someone he knew won the lottery ticket and gave it to him.
严格地说 他认识的人赢得了彩票 并把它给了他
And yeah I want friends like that.
是的 我想要这样的朋友
But honestly if Inspiration four is probably my favorite one of the missions
但说实话 如果灵感四可能是我最喜欢的任务之一
because it's just doing something very different with a lot of cool people.
因为它只是和很多很酷的人一起做一些非常不同的事情
So next up there's going to be Soyuz MS-19 and that's in October
因此 接下来将是联盟MS-19 那是在10月
and that's going to have movie director Klim Shipenko and an actress Yulia Peresild
电影导演克里姆-希彭科和女演员尤利娅-佩雷西尔德将参加这次任务
who they're going to stay on the ISS for a week to shoot scenes for a movie which is titled the Challenge.
他们将在国际空间站上停留一周 为一部名为《挑战》的电影拍摄场景
Now Klim Shipenko was the director of Salyut 7
克里姆-希彭科是《礼炮7号》的导演
and that's a movie that tells the story of the rescue and repair of the Salyut 7 space station in the 1980s
那部电影讲述的是20世纪80年代拯救和修复 "礼炮7号 "空间站的故事
and it's not a particularly accurate movie.
它不是一部特别准确的电影
It's got lots of extra events tagged on
它有很多额外的事件
but it's cool that somebody wants to make a movie about Salyut 7 right.
但有人想拍一部关于Salyut 7的电影 这很酷
Apparently there are a few other actresses in reserve
显然 还有一些其他的女演员在等待
if any problems turn up during training over the next few months.
如果在未来几个月的训练中出现任何问题
but that's what's expected to happen in October.
但这是预计在10月发生的事情
And so they'll be working by then in the newly expanded russian segment of the space station.
因此 到那时他们将在新扩建的俄罗斯空间站部分工作
They'll have Nauka planned for delivery in July
他们将有Nauka计划在7月交付
and the Prichal docking module will arrive in September.
和普里查尔对接模块将在9月到达
And these people were only staying for a few days and they will actually return.
而这些人只是停留了几天 他们将真正返回
They'll go up in MS-19 and return on MS-18.
他们将乘坐MS-19上去 然后乘坐MS-18返回
What they're doing is essentially delivering a fresh Soyuz to the crew and the ISS.
他们所做的基本上是向船员和国际空间站提供一个新的联盟号
The Soyuz needs to be replaced every six months
联盟号需要每六个月更换一次
because the hydrogen peroxide fuel for the descent module slowly decomposes over time.
因为下降舱的过氧化氢燃料会随着时间慢慢分解
So next in December we have Soyuz MS-20 and we have a familiar name and face.
因此 接下来在12月 我们将迎来联盟号MS-20 我们有一个熟悉的名字和面孔
Yusaku Maezawa the Japanese billionaire behind Dear Moon
前泽友作是《亲爱的月球》背后的日本亿万富翁
one of the big investors in Starship development.
星际飞船开发的大投资者之一
He will be making his first space flight on a Soyuz
他将在联盟号上进行他的第一次太空飞行
alongside production assistant Yozo Hirano
与制作助理平野洋三一起
who will document the flight presumably posting all over the instagram.
他将记录这次飞行 估计会在instagram上发布所有信息
And many of you might be wondering why Yusaku is not flying on a SpaceX rocket
你们中的许多人可能想知道为什么优作不乘坐SpaceX的火箭？
given that he's given SpaceX a lot of money for Starship.
因为他给了SpaceX大量的钱来购买Starship
And I think probably the main problem is that he wants to fly to the ISS
我认为主要问题可能是他想飞往国际空间站
and that means there's very limited opportunities
而这意味着机会非常有限
because NASA is controlling the number of flights in part
因为NASA正在控制飞行的数量 部分原因是
because they have very limited availability of docking slots.
因为他们有非常有限的对接名额
There's only two Pressurized Mating Adapters that have to be shared
只有两个加压对接适配器 必须在乘员舱和货运龙之间共享
between the Crew and Cargo Dragon and Starliner
在乘员和货物龙飞船和星际飞船之间共享
which incidentally looks like it's scheduled to finally fly and dock to the ISS in late July.
顺便说一下 它看起来最终计划在7月下旬飞行并与国际空间站对接
So the this Soyuz tourist flight in December is unlike the previous ones
因此 12月的这次联盟号旅游飞行与以往不同
because the crew are taking the same spacecraft up and down
因为机组人员是乘坐同一个航天器上上下下的
instead of using a short mission as an opportunity to ferry up a replacement vehicle for a crew on the station.
而不是利用短暂的任务作为一个机会 为空间站上的乘员渡过一个替代的飞行器
So this is the first time they've actually done a dedicated tourist flight up and down.
因此 这是他们第一次真正做一个专门的旅游上下行飞行
Now the first US tourist flight to the ISS will be on Axioms AX-1
现在 美国第一次飞往国际空间站的旅游飞行将由Axioms AX-1号飞机执行
and that will happen no earlier than January 2021.
而这将不早于2021年1月发生
It's going to use a Dragon spacecraft and this was actually pitched as the original.
它将使用 "龙 "飞船 这实际上是作为最初的计划
Well this was originally going to be the flight that took Tom Cruise and his director
好吧 这原本是将汤姆-克鲁斯和他的导演带去的飞行
who I think is Doug Liman to spaced
我想他是道格-利曼（Doug Liman） 前往太空
and that project has apparently been pushed out a bit for unspecified reasons.
而这个项目显然由于不明原因被推迟了一些
It's still on but we just don't know when.
它仍然在进行 但我们不知道什么时候
So the crew of AX-1 has veteran astronaut Michael López-Alegría as a commander.
因此 AX-1的船员有资深宇航员Michael López-Alegría作为指挥官
He's also the vp of Axiom and then on top of him or next to him technically sorry.
他也是Axiom的副总裁 然后在他上面或旁边的技术上对不起
There are three paying passengers. Larry Connor, real estate investor, entrepreneur.
有三名付费乘客 拉里-康纳 房地产投资者 企业家
but he's cool he's also a pilot racer. He races cars off-road and stuff.
但他很酷 他也是一个飞行员赛车手 他参加汽车越野赛之类的比赛
He also went to the bottom of the ocean.
他还去了海底
The bottom of the Challenger Deep in a submarine called the Limiting Factor.
在挑战者深渊的底部 乘坐一艘名为 "限制因素 "的潜水艇
there's Eytan Stibbe who's Israeli businessman and an investor.
还有埃坦-斯蒂贝 他是以色列商人和投资者
He also flew with the Israeli air force.
他还曾在以色列空军中飞行
And that included a stint as an F-16 pilot in a squadron commanded by Ilan Ramon
其中包括在伊兰-拉蒙指挥的一个中队担任F-16飞行员
who was Israel's first astronaut and he died in the Columbia disaster.
他是以色列的第一位宇航员 在哥伦比亚号灾难中死亡
Finally there's Canadian Mark Pathy who's a yeah he's an investor businessman
最后是加拿大人马克-帕蒂 是的 他是一个投资商人
and I'm sure he has some cool stories if you look up his background.
我肯定他有一些很酷的故事 如果你查一下他的背景
But look each of these people are there because they're investors that have made a lot of money
但你看 这些人都在那里 因为他们是投资者 已经赚了很多钱
and they like space and they had to pay 55 million dollars for the flight.
他们喜欢太空 他们不得不为这次飞行支付5500万美元
And apparently there's been recent changes to pricing for ISS operations from NASA
显然 最近美国宇航局对国际空间站运营的定价有了变化
and I think they now have to pay 10 million dollars per person
我想他们现在必须为每人支付1000万美元的费用
for the time that they're staying on the ISS
他们在国际空间站停留的时间
to cover consumables, astronaut time and things like that.
以支付消耗品、宇航员时间和类似的东西
So Axioms actually an interesting company for another reason
因此 Axioms实际上是一家有趣的公司 还有一个原因
because they are also contracted to develop and deliver new modules to the ISS
因为他们也被签约开发并向国际空间站提供新的模块
to expand its commercial capabilities
以扩大其商业能力
and this is going to start with a single module that's going to berth to the very front of the station
这将从一个单一的模块开始 该模块将停靠在空间站的最前面
where PMA-2 is the docking adapter currently.
目前PMA-2是对接适配器
They're going to take that off and dock a new module on there
他们将把它拆下来 然后把一个新的模块停靠在那里
and this module looks like it's actually going to bring its own docking adapter
而这个模块看起来实际上将带来它自己的对接适配器
which will probably allow NASA to move that existing docking adapter to a new location
这将可能允许NASA将现有的对接适配器移到一个新的位置上
and that will mean that they'll hopefully have 3 parking slots and a little more availability.
这将意味着他们有希望获得3个停车位和更多的可用性
Long term Axiom might as add as many as three modules to the space station
长期而言 Axiom可能会在空间站中增加多达三个模块
with a focus on providing accommodation for tourists
重点是为游客提供住宿
and with an eye to potentially converting this to a free flying station in the future.
并着眼于将来有可能将其转化为自由飞行站
But for now that is a pretty busy schedule
但就目前而言 这是一个相当繁忙的时间表
to compare between 2001 and 2009 there were 8 private astronaut flights over 8 years.
相比之下 在2001年和2009年之间 8年内有8次私人宇航员飞行
7 people in total because one of them wants to go twice.
总共7个人 因为其中一个人想去两次
Now in the next 12 months we're gonna have more tourists than that whole 8 years.
现在在接下来的12个月里 我们的游客会比那8年整整多
And that's pretty darn cool.
这真是太酷了
I mean sure it is way out of my price range.
我的意思是 这当然超出了我的价格范围
I mean even the suborbital stuff would probably need me to like work with the bank and remortgage my house
我的意思是 即使是亚轨道的东西也可能需要我与银行合作 重新抵押我的房子
and frankly I have a family to raise and I'm not going to do that
坦率地说 我有一个家庭要抚养 我不打算这样做
but maybe by the time I'm done with that the prices will have dropped to a more manageable level
但也许在我完成这些工作的时候 价格将下降到一个更容易管理的水平
and I might actually get to fly on one of these things.
而且我可能真的会有机会乘坐这些东西
So here's hoping for a great future of tourism and accessibility to space.
因此 我们希望未来的旅游业和太空的可及性能有一个很好的发展
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是斯科特-曼利 飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]